nixcraft.com 2014-06-29

# Privacy policy - nixCraft

This site http://www.cyberciti.biz and http://nixcraft.com [ our forum ] ("nixCraft") hosts the project, documents, and tutorials related to open source software's, Linux, FreeBSD and UNIX (Solaris) etc., largely compiled and maintained by Vivek Gite or by project contributors. We do not ask for any registration except registration is compulsory only if:

  * You wish to post your message on our forum.
  * You wish to post comments on our blogs or tutorials.

Forum software and other registration softwares create your profile and collect your personal information such as email address, your name, instant massager ids etc. We do not share this information with any other entity. In addition, a confirmation from the email address is required, to prevent anyone from subscribing to forum or wiki someone else without permission. Subscription to our wiki or forum will not start until confirmation is received. Requests to be removed from the wiki and forum will result in deletion of the email address and other profile information.

### Mailing list

Visitors are invited to join our mailing list. No information, except an e-mail address is required for this. In addition, a confirmation from the email address is required, to prevent anyone from subscribing someone else without permission. Subscription to our mailing list will not start until confirmation is received. Requests to be removed from the mailing list will result in deletion of the email address.

All the information provided or collected by us will only be used within cyberciti.biz and will not be sold, rented, loaned or traded with a third party, except where required by law.

If offensive content is posted or sent anywhere on or to cyberciti.biz or a visitor engages in any disruptive behavior on cyberciti.biz, we can use whatever information is available to stop such behavior. This may involve informing relevant third parties such as employers, web hosting service provider, e-mail/Internet providers and law enforcement agencies about the content and behavior.

### Log Files

nixCraft collect and use the data contained in server log files. The information in the log files include your IP address, ISP, the browser you used to visit this site, the date & time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site.

### Google Analytics

We also use Google Analytics on this website. A small amount of **anonymous data** is sends to the Google's servers such as your ISP, browser, operating system, geo-location and so on. We use this reports to improve our site's articles (content), and design for our visitors. Google Analytics put cookies on your computer. Please see the [Google Analytics Terms of Service](http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html) for more information.

### Cookies and Web Beacons

We do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit our site.

#### Advertising and Third-party ads

Because of effective Internet advertising, the content is free to you. We do accept advertising on our site. These advertising or advertiser put cookies on your computer and by clicking on external links on this website, you will be visiting independent sites which have separate privacy policies .

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, you may visit ad vendor websites to opt out of cookies (if the vendor offers this capability).

##### Links to the vendor websites to opt out:

  * DoubleClick DFA and RichMedia ([www.doubleclick.com](http://www.doubleclick.com/))
  * Collective ([www.collective.com](http://www.collective.com/))
  * IDG Technetwork ([www.idgtechnetwork.com](http://www.idgtechnetwork.com/))
  * Mediaplex/ValueClick ([www.mediaplex.com](http://www.mediaplex.com/))
  * Eyeblaster ([www.eyeblaster.com](http://www.eyeblaster.com/))
  * EyeWonder ([www.eyewonder.com](http://www.eyewonder.com/))
  * Interpolls ([www.interpolls.com](http://www.interpolls.com/))
  * Pointroll ([www.pointroll.com](http://www.pointroll.com/))
  * Unicast ([www.unicast.com](http://www.unicast.com/))
  * Dynamic Logic/Safecount ([www.safecount.net](http://www.safecount.net/))
  * Factor TG ([www.factortg.com](http://www.factortg.com/))
  * IAG ([www.iagr.com](http://www.iagr.net/))
  * InsightExpress ([www.insightexpress.com](http://www.insightexpress.com/))
  * Google Adsense ([www.google.com/adsense](http://www.google.com/adsense))
  * Tribalfusion ([www.tribalfusion.com](http://www.tribalfusion.com/))
  * Adify ([www.adify.com](http://www.adify.com/))

##### Google Advertising Cookie and Privacy Policies

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on Site.
  * Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to Site and other sites on the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html) policy.

Visitors are invited to email us with questions or comments. Information sent will not be shared with any other entity. Email addresses are required to allow us to reply, but we do not collect email addresses from these submissions.

### Why do you want to know my name and e-mail address?

Add your name or email only if you need to follow discussion via email and/or you want to comment on our blog or tutorials.

### Do you collect information from children?

No. This site is not directed to children under the age of 13. nixCraft does not knowingly collect, or wish to obtain, personally identifiable information from children.

### How do you verify parental consent for information about their children?

We don’t.

### How do you use information collected from "Google Analytics" and log files?

nixCraft may use the anonymous data or information to improve this site, including, but not limited to:

  * To understand a user’s needs and create content that is relevant to the user;
  * To generate statistical studies;
  * To communicate back to the user;
  * To personalize a Site for the user;
  * To notify the user of any changes with a Site which may affect the user;
  * To enforce terms of use on a Site

### Do you share my information with other parts of your company?

No.

### Do you share my information with other companies?

No.

### Do you sell my information to anyone?

No.

### How can I start or stop receiving e-mail from you?

Simply click on unsubscribe link in e-mail.

### Who can I talk to if I have a question about my privacy?

Questions regarding Site policy, should be directed to us via e-mail only. This privacy policy may be updated from time to time so you may wish to check it each time you submit personal information to Site. The date of the most recent revisions will appear on this page.

Please note that this privacy policy is subject to change without any prior notice to visitors.

Last updates on: Oct-9-2012, 7:27 PM IST.
